the final thing will look at in terms of combining queries is exclusion
we used the exclusion activity to exclude unwanted query results
most businesses typically have a standard definition of who they want to exclude from their target
you can add a topology rule that will be applied during analysis to exclude these people
but you can also exclude them upfront in your workflow to get a more accurate count
to apply standard exclusions
start with your target population
and then define one or more additional queries to choose the recipients you want to exclude
and then use an exclusion activity to exclude that group of people from the main target
there are out of the box predefined user filters
which are useful for excluding recipients
such as blacklisted email
an email and quarantine
or you can always define your own filters to exclude recipients
and then save them for reuse
to define your own filter for reuse
either go to the predefined filter folder and click new
so from the explorer view under profiles and targets
going to predefined filters and click new
or you can edit a query activity
define your filtering conditions and then save it as a predefined filter
so you'll see save as highlighted it's right next to the distribution of values icon that's where you find the save option
then you would simply give that predefined filter
a label
and then you can use that again in the future
remember
the main thing for this type of filter
is that you are filtering for people that you do not
want to target
for example you might not want to target anyone whose email was empty they'll get dropped from analysis know during the analysis period anyway
or you might want to drop anyone that's an internal employee
or if you have any adobe campaign consultants who are in your data mart
as test records that sort of thing
or if you have any competitors in your database you might want to drop those domains
so that's the only tricky thing is that you are
building of
filter for people that you don't want a target
then in your workflow
you would add an exclusion activity
and attach that exclusion activity
to the query results in your workflow
and the exclusion activity as we said the whole point is to remove one or more populations from the main population
so as a result
there should be the same number
or fewer recipients in the primary set
after an exclusion
so our example here we're looking for people who are over forty five and our first query
and our second query were cheering for people whose email is empty
now if we had the email address for all of those people who are forty five years and older
we wouldn't be dropping anyone but in this example
it looks like we went from a hundred and five
forty five year olds
down to ninety five
so we were in fact missing some email addresses
for those folks who are over forty five and our training environment
now the one
other important thing to note about an exclusion activity is that you must edit it
so double click on the exclusion activity
to add it
when you double click on the exclusion activity this is what you see
you must
configure this by selecting
the group that you want to keep
so you must identify the primary set
so in this case it would have been our men over forty five
or in our example that we're going to build in the lab
we'll keep our men
under thirty who live in either new york or la
you could if you want
generate the compliment
to see the people that fell out
so the people that you're excluding
so let's go do exercise for
part five
in our lab handbook
we're going to add another query activity to our segmentation workflow
an edit that query activity
were to choose filtering conditions as the target type
and we're gonna take advantage of the predefined filter that exists in here
for blacklisted email address
and then we're gonna add some
filtering criteria on top of that
so rather than just adding an expression i'm going to click on the drop down arrow
by ad
and then scroll down to predefined filter
and then take advantage of these predefined filters that come out of the box
i'm in a pick blacklisted email address
i'm going to add another expression
as we mentioned earlier by default every time you add an expression
they are combined with an and to change this one i want this to be an or instead i'm simply gonna click on and
and then
change this or
for my second expression i'm gonna click in
edit the expression
and i'm going to choose
email
choose the email attribute
and for my operator
i'm in a select is empty
click finish
and okay
i can save that
workflow if i would like
next are gonna drag and exclusion activity from the targeting palette
so exclusion
drag that
and i'm gonna attach it to my intersection
and i am also going to attach my blacklisted email address or email is empty query to the exclusion activity
now we just covered in the slides that you must edit the exclusion activity
so we must double click on this
and select the primary group that we are keeping
so the primary set going to click the drop down arrow
i don't want to keep the people who are blacklisted or whose email is empty
i in fact want to keep the men under thirty who live in either new york or la so that's my intersection group
sentinel ct intersection
and click ok
and then i'm gonna restart that workflow
click yes
and it looks like we've dropped two people
if i wanted to see who was dropped i could bring that information in by including
the compliment
so i could doubleclick on my exclusion
check the box to generate the compliment
click ok
and i could restart this workflow
and i could see who is in the complement group
by then right clicking on this transition arrow
displaying the target
and i could see in fact that joe parker and francis jimenez have been excluded
i could always configure my list
to bring in
age
gender
email
and by deduction
i can see that i have joe parker's email address
so he must have been dropped
because he has opted out of our marketing communications
so he is considered to be blacklisted
i could then if i wanted to go verify by looking at joe parker's actual recipient account if i wanted to
francis jimenez i can see i'm missing his email
so
he most likely was dropped because we don't have his email address
so that concludes exercise four part five
one